<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 10:15:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>DIY and e-commerce: How to breathe new life into a traditional market</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/diy-e-commerce-breathe-new-life-traditional-market/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/diy-e-commerce-breathe-new-life-traditional-market/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 10:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mvalenza]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22420</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The Spanish company SelfPackaging recently breathed new life into a traditional and widely marketed product by developing a comprehensive range of fully customizable and easy-to-assemble packaging. SelfPackaging launched in 2009 and now enjoys international success thanks to its unique and attractively priced DIY solution for companies and individuals. In this video, Josep Maria Garrofé, founder [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/diy-e-commerce-breathe-new-life-traditional-market/">DIY and e-commerce: How to breathe new life into a traditional market</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Spanish company SelfPackaging recently breathed new life into a traditional and widely marketed product by developing a comprehensive range of fully customizable and easy-to-assemble packaging.<span id="more-22420"></span></p>
<p><a href="http://selfpackaging.com/" target="_blank">SelfPackaging</a> launched in 2009 and now enjoys international success thanks to its unique and attractively priced DIY solution for companies and individuals.</p>
<p>In this video, Josep Maria Garrofé, founder of SelfPackaging, and David Rodriguez, CEO of WebImpacto (the web agency that developed the latest version of the e-commerce website) give advice to help you succeed in this very unique business.</p>
<p>Learn from their expertise and advice, and improve your e-commerce website!</p>
<div class="g-ytsubscribe col-centered text-center" data-channelid="UCqDSbqSbkboMBARlYrhNa7g" data-layout="full" data-count="default"></div>
<p><iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/E9N4isW8TSI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div class="text-center"><a class="btn" style="background-color: #cd201f;border: 1px solid #b31217;border-bottom: 3px solid #b31217;margin: 20px 0 0;color: #fff" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/prestashop?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=article&amp;utm_campaign=youtube&amp;utm_content=leslipfrancais"> Watch more videos</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/diy-e-commerce-breathe-new-life-traditional-market/">DIY and e-commerce: How to breathe new life into a traditional market</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/diy-e-commerce-breathe-new-life-traditional-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Last minute tips before Black Friday</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/last-minute-tips-black-friday/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/last-minute-tips-black-friday/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 10:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Trends]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22409</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>As the Romans may have said on a day like today: “Barbari qui in porta sunt.”. In a more familiar tongue, “The Barbarians are at the gate”. Not that we’d want you to consider your customers to be barbarous, but as we all know, Black Friday has been known to elicit scenes of customers stampeding [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/last-minute-tips-black-friday/">Last minute tips before Black Friday</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">As the Romans may have said on a day like today: “Barbari qui in porta sunt.”. In a more familiar tongue, “The Barbarians are at the gate”. Not that we’d want you to consider your customers to be barbarous, but as we all know, Black Friday has been known to elicit scenes of customers stampeding into retail stores in order to scoop up the best deals.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span id="more-22409"></span>In the E-commerce world, if you’re in B2C retail, this is what you’ve been prepping for in recent weeks and months -<strong> a rush of shoppers</strong>, well rested after a massive Thanksgiving feast, and ready to conquer the first round of their holiday shopping.</p>
<p dir="ltr">With so much on the line, don’t forget to conduct some <strong>last minute checks to make sure that you’re ready</strong>. We recommend the following:</p>
<ul>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Check with your host to make sure that your <strong>hosting account is ready</strong> for the influx of traffic</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Make sure that you know how to reach<strong> hosting support 24/7</strong> should something go wrong</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Confirm that you have a <strong>contact list for other vendors</strong>, like your credit card processors and other 3rd party services, should you run into any issues</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Know the <strong>availability of your developers</strong> should you run into issues that aren’t related to hosting</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Test any coupons or discounts</strong> that you’ll be applying to make sure that they work as intended, as well as any holiday banners and graphics</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Complete a final sweep of your site, <strong>testing from the homepage, through checkout</strong> just in case any last-minute updates caused any unnoticed issues</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Confirm that your <strong>marketing campaigns</strong>, such as for ReMarketing, are turned on, have the necessary budgets, and are ready to go</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Ensure that you’re <strong>tracking the traffic</strong> to your site through a system like Google Analytics</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Add a date to your calendar</strong>, closer to New Year’s, to review your analytics and data, and start thinking about how to have an even better holiday shopping season in 2017!</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p dir="ltr">At this point, you don’t have time for significant changes, but it’s always best to be prepared for the worst, giving you a better opportunity to rise to the occasion and thwart any glitches should problems arise. Knowing which vendors provide you with which services is a key to that success &#8211; when the chips are down, you want to start by going to the support team that can solve the problem first.</p>
<p dir="ltr">While we know that you’ll be focused on your short-term needs in the coming weeks, this is your opportunity to commit to great planning for next year. So many businesses wait until the last minute to plan for the holiday shopping season. Our experience shows that <strong>the most successful sites are reviewing data and game planning in January</strong>, allowing them to optimize their websites and marketing campaigns for conversions all year long. This way when the holidays come, they’re at the top of their game. If in a few weeks you feel like you could have had a better season, don’t despair! Focus those energies on a having an amazing 2017 Black Friday!</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">About the author</span></p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Robert Rand, Chief Technology Officer, <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners/bronze/randmarketing" target="_blank">RandMarketing.com</a></strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Rand Marketing is an award winning full-service digital agency, based in Fort Lauderdale, FL, with an in-house team of designers, developers, and digital marketing specialists. Whether you need help with Search Engine Optimization, Google AdWords and Pay Per Click Marketing, Social Media Marketing, E-mail Marketing, Web Design, Conversion Rate Optimization, or other E-commerce needs, the Rand Team is here to help. We’re Google Premier Partners, an INC5000 company, and have an A+ with the BBB, among our many accolades.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><img alt="" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/MndfWLQqEUvfWDEBHGQHvMQU6qT9Ghv6FiXFFTDvF5LAvmqP9iD1oHHuJRRn77nygZARlylPxOdyljTNcn6HbCNJo1FYSbskwUALPajt_7ptHEi9ZLbUHNJLDUfNGjSml7JG3zc1" width="349" height="85" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/last-minute-tips-black-friday/">Last minute tips before Black Friday</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/last-minute-tips-black-friday/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Your Online Retail Site Could Benefit from using Instagram</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-retail-site-benefit-using-instagram/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-retail-site-benefit-using-instagram/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 16:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22390</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>2016 has been Instagram’s year. It now has over 500 million monthly users (more than Twitter!) and 60% log in daily, making it the second most engaged network after Facebook. Instagram is also proving to be a near-ideal platform for brands &#8211; particularly ecommerce brands. 70% of Instagram users report already having looked up a brand [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-retail-site-benefit-using-instagram/">How Your Online Retail Site Could Benefit from using Instagram</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>2016 has been Instagram’s year. It now has over <a href="https://www.instagram.com/press/" target="_blank">500 million monthly users</a> (more than Twitter!) and 60% log in daily, making it the second most engaged network after Facebook.<br />
<span id="more-22390"></span></p>
<p>Instagram is also proving to be a near-ideal platform for brands &#8211; particularly ecommerce brands. 70% of Instagram users report already having <a href="http://blog.iconosquare.com/instagram-2015-study-unleash-power-instagram/" target="_blank">looked up a brand on the platform</a> and, according to research from member-based intelligence firm L2, Instagram has the highest <a href="http://business.financialpost.com/investing/trading-desk/how-instagram-is-becoming-a-must-have-for-retailers?__lsa=6904-3bfd" target="_blank">browser-to-shopper conversion rate</a> of all the social networks.</p>
<p>So it’s really time to take Instagram seriously yet only <a href="http://www.emarketer.com/Article/Small-Businesses-So-So-About-Social/1012348" target="_blank">9% of US small businesses</a> are posting regularly on the network.  Read on to discover why Instagram should be part of the marketing strategy for your online retail site.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #00ccff;">1.  Showcase your product catalogue</span></h2>
<p>The creative spirit of Instagram gives you real scope to showcase your products in unique and inspirational ways. Avoid being overly commercial; users respond well to beautiful, professional-looking images that communicate your brand’s value without needing a sales pitch.</p>
<p>Although this may seem easier for fashion and beauty brands which focus on an attractive product catalogue, less visually appealing brands such as <a href="https://www.instagram.com/staples/" target="_blank">Staples</a> and home improvement chain <a href="https://www.instagram.com/loweshomeimprovement/" target="_blank">Lowes</a> have created inventive strategies to communicate their brand offerings in way that engages users:</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/11/lowes.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-22392" alt="lowes" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/11/lowes.jpg" width="1413" height="916" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/11/staples.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-22393" alt="staples" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/11/staples.jpg" width="1418" height="913" /></a></p>
<h2><span style="color: #00ccff;">2.  Build a brand personality and engage followers</span></h2>
<p>User engagement with brands is <a href="https://www.brandwatch.com/blog/37-instagram-stats-2016/" target="_blank">10 times higher on Instagram than Facebook</a>. As well as product images, you can test posting videos, quotes, statistics and run contests and see which your followers responds to best.</p>
<p>A great way to develop your brand’s personality on Instagram is also to post fun behind-the-scenes images or video clips of your products being made or what day-to-day life is like at your company. This can also help for recruiting new staff as they get a great idea of what it will be like to work for your brand.</p>
<p>Another option, particularly for small businesses, is to post images of your local area to help build your brand personality. Adding geotags showing where the photo was taken can also help attract new followers.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/11/humming.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-22394" alt="humming" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/11/humming.jpg" width="1432" height="920" /></a></p>
<h2><span style="color: #00ccff;">3.  Drive online sales</span></h2>
<p>Ok so now you’ve built up an online community with your beautiful product photos and behind the scenes lifestyle shots &#8211; how does that translate into revenue? Well if you’re doing things right, you may already be seeing results as 78% of consumers make <a href="http://www.socialmediatoday.com/marketing/masroor/2015-05-28/social-media-biggest-influencer-buying-decisions" target="_blank">buying decisions influenced by a brand’s social media</a>. Another extremely effective option is to post exclusive limited-time offers for your followers to motivate them to buy.</p>
<p>However if you want a more concrete (and measurable) way to drive sales from within the platform then you should considering investing in Instagram ads. The <a href="https://www.elegantthemes.com/blog/resources/5-social-commerce-trends-to-watch-out-for-in-2016" target="_blank">average order value</a> of Instagram-referred orders is $65 compared to $55 for Facebook and $46.29 for Twitter.</p>
<p>Ads can take the form of a photo or video with a call to action such as Shop Now, Install Now or Sign Up. Currently ads drive shoppers to your site to make the purchase but Instagram are already testing <a href="http://marketingland.com/instagram-tests-shopping-outside-ads-20-retailers-u-s-196761" target="_blank">enabling purchases from within the app</a> itself which will probably lead to even higher conversion rates.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://blog.business.instagram.com/post/128686033016/150909-advertisinglaunch" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-22395" alt="Instagram ads" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/11/Instagram-ads.jpg" width="1200" height="525" /></a></p>
<p>So there you have it, three great reasons why you should consider testing out Instagram for your online retail site!</p>
<p><i>SteerFox is an intelligent advertising automation tool which helps online retailers get results from their ad campaigns on Instagram, Facebook, Google Adwords and Google Shopping. Find out more at </i><a href="http://www.steerfox.com/en/" target="_blank"><i>steerfox.com</i></a><i>.</i></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-retail-site-benefit-using-instagram/">How Your Online Retail Site Could Benefit from using Instagram</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-retail-site-benefit-using-instagram/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Effectively Using Social Networks for Your E-commerce Site</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/effectively-using-social-networks-e-commerce-site/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/effectively-using-social-networks-e-commerce-site/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 15:28:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mvalenza]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22373</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Today, having a presence on social media is essential for promoting your e-commerce site&#8217;s visibility. You&#8217;re surely already familiar with Facebook, Twitter and Pinterest and use them for personal accounts. However, using these networks to boost your e-commerce site is no easy task! To succeed in developing your community—and visibility—on social media, you need to: [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/effectively-using-social-networks-e-commerce-site/">Effectively Using Social Networks for Your E-commerce Site</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today, having a presence on social media is essential for promoting your e-commerce site&#8217;s visibility. You&#8217;re surely already familiar with Facebook, Twitter and Pinterest and use them for personal accounts. <span id="more-22373"></span>However, using these networks to boost your e-commerce site is no easy task!<br />
To succeed in developing your community—and visibility—on social media, you need to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Use the most relevant social networks,</li>
<li>Target your posts,</li>
<li>Propose suitable content,</li>
<li>And be active enough to be effective!</li>
</ul>
<p>Watch the video with our advice to help you improve your effectiveness on social networks!</p>
<p>BONUS: Holiday shopping has started! At the end of this video, you&#8217;ll find our tips to be even more effective on social media during this crucial season!</p>
<div class="g-ytsubscribe col-centered text-center" data-channelid="UCqDSbqSbkboMBARlYrhNa7g" data-layout="full" data-count="default"></div>
<p><iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eUP-Cp4gbp8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div class="text-center"><a class="btn" style="background-color: #cd201f;border: 1px solid #b31217;border-bottom: 3px solid #b31217;margin: 20px 0 0;color: #fff" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/prestashop?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=article&amp;utm_campaign=youtube&amp;utm_content=prestashopsocialmedia"> Watch more videos</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/effectively-using-social-networks-e-commerce-site/">Effectively Using Social Networks for Your E-commerce Site</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/effectively-using-social-networks-e-commerce-site/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Design Tips for a Successful Holiday Website</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/design-tips-successful-holiday-website/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/design-tips-successful-holiday-website/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 15:01:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Camille Sila]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22379</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>One of the best things about online shopping at the holidays is that consumers skip the high street madness: parking, waiting in long lines, discovering there’s no more paper just as they reach the gift wrap counter. But shopping online can also be daunting, especially for customers who have a long list and no clue [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/design-tips-successful-holiday-website/">Design Tips for a Successful Holiday Website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the best things about online shopping at the holidays is that consumers skip the high street madness: parking, waiting in long lines, discovering there’s no more paper just as they reach the gift wrap counter.</p>
<p>But shopping online can also be daunting, especially for customers who have a long list and no clue what to buy. Try some of these design ideas to simplify the purchasing process and give your customers&#8211;new and returning alike&#8211;a fun, festive online shopping experience.<br />
<span id="more-22379"></span></p>
<hr />
<h1 style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #00ccff;">Design Checklist</span></h1>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/11/Checklist_designTips-EN-copie.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-22380" alt="Checklist_designTips" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/11/Checklist_designTips-EN-copie.jpg" width="1200" height="2245" /></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/design-tips-successful-holiday-website/">Design Tips for a Successful Holiday Website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/design-tips-successful-holiday-website/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to get your e-commerce site ready for the Holiday season?</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-e-commerce-site-ready-holiday-season/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-e-commerce-site-ready-holiday-season/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 15:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22367</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>It’s a fact: Christmas is coming and with it comes a batch of excitement and preparation. Every year the digital agency NewQuest, a PrestaShop Platinum Partner, shares their “10 commandments” for getting your online store ready! By our web agency partner NewQuest. 1. Thou shalt optimize time At this time of year, the expression “time [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-e-commerce-site-ready-holiday-season/">How to get your e-commerce site ready for the Holiday season?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s a fact: Christmas is coming and with it comes a batch of excitement and preparation. Every year the digital agency NewQuest, a PrestaShop Platinum Partner, shares their “10 commandments” for getting your online store ready! </p>
<p><span id="more-22367"></span></p>
<p>By our web agency partner <a href="http://www.newquest-group.com/index_en.php">NewQuest</a>. </p>
<p><strong>1.	Thou shalt optimize time<br />
</strong></p>
<p>At this time of year, the expression “time is money” has never been more true. And when you want to save time, Store Commander might be the exact tool you’ve been looking for! Don&#8217;t worry about managing your back office… The 360° view and unique features will allow you to make a number of changes and updates in just a few seconds. Completely integrated with PrestaShop, Store Commander makes it easier and faster for you to manage your catalog and special offers at the holidays.</p>
<p><strong>2.	Thou shalt decorate thy store<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Dress up your site for Christmas to make it attractive and dynamic. You’ll have a better chance of attracting attention and, as a consequence, getting visitors to stay on your site with those holiday decorations. Target your design, content and images towards the products that are most appealing at Christmas. Highlight those bestsellers so it’s easier for shoppers to find them. </p>
<p><strong>3.	Thou shalt increase thy visibility<br />
</strong></p>
<p>75% of consumers are influenced by displays and it’s a fact: advertising impacts the brand people choose, the place where they purchase, and the type of gift they buy. It’s therefore important to choose your target audience and create compelling advertising campaigns for them. You can also reinforce your online presence by putting up sponsored advertising on social networks like Facebook or Instagram. </p>
<p>Don’t forget to send a special Christmas newsletter to your customers! These are loyal buyers who will appreciate hearing from you, and they’re highly likely to respond.</p>
<p><strong>4.	Thou shalt take care of thy SEO<br />
</strong></p>
<p>77% of internet users find their online gifts with search engines, and 33% of e-commerce website traffic comes from SEO. In this crucial period, you normally don&#8217;t have enough time; that’s why you really should combine your SEO strategy with an SEM strategy on Google Adwords.</p>
<p><strong>5.	Thou shalt show transparency<br />
</strong></p>
<p>It’s vital to put essential information for visitors up-front. This includes payment, delivery, returns, gift wrapping, etc. 40% of people feel more confident if the site offers several payment methods. 60% will also abandon their order if their preferred payment method is not offered. PayPal manages 60% of the internet’s financial transactions and is one of the most popular payment systems, as an example. </p>
<p><strong>6.	Thou shalt be flexible<br />
</strong></p>
<p>If delivery fees are too high, there’s a risk that visitors will abandon their orders. 59% of visitors attach high importance to delivery fees before making their purchase decision. If they’re too high, half are ready to change vendors. Delivery offers are essential for e-commerce performance.</p>
<p>With that in mind, we highly recommend offering express home delivery or a delivery point like drop-off points, click &amp; collect, etc. </p>
<p><strong>7.	Thou shalt be present on all devices<br />
</strong></p>
<p>In 2015, mobiles and tablets accounted for 54% of traffic to e-commerce sites during the holiday period. But of equal importance was the amount of sales that came from these devices. Over 1/3 of purchases at the holidays was attributed to mobile, which is an increase of 35% from the previous year. We can’t repeat it enough: having a site that is adapted to mobile and tablet devices isn&#8217;t an option, it’s a requirement. </p>
<p><strong>8.	Thou shalt be involved in m-commerce<br />
</strong></p>
<p>In 2016, mobile will account for 23.6% of spending in France, as one example. In Europe, we estimate that m-commerce represents a potential 65 billion euros. Mobile commerce will allow you to reach new customers and target more effectively through push notifications, SMS messages, applications, and even geolocalization.</p>
<p><strong>9.	Though shalt convert through social commerce<br />
</strong></p>
<p>It’s not big news… Social networks will help millions of shoppers, who are looking for holiday inspiration, to make their purchasing decisions. They’re a gold mine for the retail season. Facebook, Instagram, Pinterest, and YouTube; these channels enable shoppers to find product reviews and recommendations from others. They’re communications channels that simply can’t be missed. </p>
<p><strong>10.	Thou shalt anticipate traffic to thy server<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Contact your web hosting provider to discuss your store’s traffic limits and the possibility of temporarily increasing your hosting service. Many qualified servers should be able to handle an increase in traffic without requiring you to upgrade to a higher plan. Analyze last year’s data as well as that of your competitors in order to get a preview of what could happen in months of November and December. If you need to upgrade to a higher plan, make sure you know how long the process will take so you’re ready for the sales period. </p>
<p>You also need to consider reducing the size of your CSS (Cascading Style Sheets). Get rid of useless space between information, compress and resize your images (above all, check the size of an image compared to the version on the site). To save time, concentrate your efforts on your homepage and best sellers.</p>
<p><strong>Dreaded by some, eagerly awaited by others, Christmas is the event of the year for those in e-retail. Plan ahead and please take our advice because it could be invaluable!<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Follow the <strong>#JingleDays campaign by PrestaShop</strong> on <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/JingleDays?src=hash">Twitter </a>and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/prestashop/">Facebook</a>.</p>
<p><em>Sources :<br />
- http://www.ma-creation-ecommerce.com/e-commerce-bien-se-preparer-pour-noel/<br />
- http://www.vision-ecommerce.com/e-commerce-reussir-periode-noel/<br />
- http://blog.lengow.com/fr/bonnes-pratiques/e-commerce-10-commandements-noel/</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-e-commerce-site-ready-holiday-season/">How to get your e-commerce site ready for the Holiday season?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-e-commerce-site-ready-holiday-season/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>PrestaShop 1.7: answers to all of your questions</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-1-7-answers-questions/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-1-7-answers-questions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 11:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xavier Borderie]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22364</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>PrestaShop has launched PrestaShop 1.7, the latest software version. It was developed with the help of user feedback from the last few years. Today, over 250,000 online stores use PrestaShop to sell their products. What do these sellers need to know? 1. My store is running on an older version (1.4, 1.5, or 1.6). Do [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-1-7-answers-questions/">PrestaShop 1.7: answers to all of your questions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>PrestaShop has launched <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/1.7">PrestaShop 1.7</a>, the latest software version. It was developed with the help of user feedback from the last few years.</p>
<p>Today, over 250,000 online stores use PrestaShop to sell their products. What do these sellers need to know?</p>
<p><span id="more-22364"></span></p>
<p><strong>1.   	My store is running on an older version (1.4, 1.5, or 1.6). Do I have to upgrade to version 1.7 immediately?<br />
</strong></p>
<p>There is no obligation. Your current store will continue to function as it always has, so don&#8217;t feel rushed. You have enough on your plate preparing for holiday shopping and Winter and Christmas sales.</p>
<p>If you would like to move up to version 1.7, keep in mind that it is a major version of PrestaShop, so updating will require you proceed with caution, and perhaps even <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners">ask for assistance</a>.<br />
That is because the template system has been rewritten, so your theme will either have to be changed or entirely rewritten. Additionally, your modules will need to be carefully examined and likely adapted, at least in terms of design.</p>
<p>In fact, consider updating to version 1.7 to be a big project that could take several days to prepare, even before you start migrating your data.</p>
<p><strong>2.   	Has version 1.6 been suspended?<br />
</strong><br />
Of course not! The recent update 1.6.1.9 is proof of that. We will continue to maintain PrestaShop version 1.6 in the long run. To be more specific, it will continue to be supported by our teams for two years after the release of 1.7. In other words, until October 2018. Expect other minor updates to version 1.6 in the coming months. They will fix the bugs reported by the community—and you are more than welcome to help us squash some more with your comments!</p>
<p><strong>3.   	How can I upgrade my store to 1.7?</strong></p>
<p>Developers are updating the one-click upgrade module to work with the transition to version 1.7. Take note that this module will only deal with your store&#8217;s data. The theme and modules will be those used by default, and your theme from version 1.5/1.6 will be deactivated, as will all of your third-party modules. Be sure to consider that before updating!<br />
We strongly recommend you get in touch with <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners">our partner agencies and developers</a> to make sure that your move to version 1.7 goes off without a hitch.</p>
<p><strong>4. What if I have questions about 1.7? Where can I get help?<br />
</strong><br />
-<a href="https://www.prestashop.com/forums/?lang=en"> The community forum</a>, for help from other members<br />
- <a href="http://forge.prestashop.com/secure/Dashboard.jspa">Forge, PrestaShop&#8217;s bug tracker</a>, if you have any bugs to report<br />
- <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/support">PrestaShop Technical Support</a>, for any additional help<br />
- Find out more with FAQ on PrestaShop 1.7 in <a href="http://build.prestashop.com/news/prestashop-1-7-faq/">Build.prestashop.com </a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-1-7-answers-questions/">PrestaShop 1.7: answers to all of your questions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-1-7-answers-questions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cross-device retargeting: reaching customers on all their devices</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/cross-device-retargeting-reaching-customers-devices/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/cross-device-retargeting-reaching-customers-devices/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eva Lacalle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22341</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Well, Google has finally begun to implement changes that will enable advertisers to reach potential customers across all their devices in retargeting campaigns. It might have seemed like a trivial change, but the fact is,  until now, the ways in which Google allowed user data to be used in remarketing (Google’s term for retargeting) campaigns [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/cross-device-retargeting-reaching-customers-devices/">Cross-device retargeting: reaching customers on all their devices</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Google has finally begun to implement changes that will enable advertisers to <b>reach potential customers across all their devices in retargeting campaigns.</b> It might have seemed like a trivial change, but the fact is,  until now, the ways in which Google allowed user data to be used in remarketing (Google’s term for retargeting) campaigns were limited.<br />
<span id="more-22341"></span><br />
To understand exactly <b>what cross-device retargeting means,</b> we need to look at what currently happens within this type of advertising activity. Imagine a potential customer visiting your website or blog from their mobile phone on their way to work. When they arrive at their office, they continue browsing on their computer. As an advertiser, you can’t reconnect with that consumer unless they come back to your website from the second device. And this is just the first limitation of retargeting as we currently know it.</p>
<p>If the person does decide to return to your website from their computer, they will be listed twice. This affects the frequency capping set by an advertiser on a retargeting campaign, since it applies to each device independently. This result in products being displayed more frequently than desired per person and impeding other potential customers from seeing the brand.</p>
<p>Ultimately, this restricts your marketing campaign in two ways: one, by <b>not being able to retarget users browsing on different devices</b>; and two, <b>impacting your marketing campaign budget </b>if that person returns to your store or blog from another device. They can’t ever be counted as the same user and will instead be listed as a new user. This reduces the effectiveness of retargeting campaigns.</p>
<h4 style="color: #5cc6ff">Why can’t we retarget across multiple devices?</h4>
<p>We can’t retarget across multiple devices at the same time because of the way the advertising system works. Basically, it relies on <b>cookies that are stored on the device</b> each time we browse the internet.</p>
<p>These files are downloaded to our browser whenever we visit a website, so they are only useful for retargeting if we visit the website from the same browser. This means cookies from our mobile, computer or tablet are not available on our other devices.</p>
<p>Until now, Google has relied on cookies and mobile IDs to identify users, without taking into account that they could be coming to our website from, for example, Google Chrome, logged into their account across all devices. This is something that Facebook <i>had</i> already taken into account. With a retargeting system that relies on cookies, the campaign does not work across our potential customer’s different devices, and we can only display our products or brand on the one device they used to visit our website.</p>
<h4 style="color: #5cc6ff">What changes does Google’s cross-device remarketing bring?</h4>
<p>With this change, announced at <b>#GoogleAW2016</b>, advertisers will be able to reach the same user across all their devices. Brad Bender, VP of display and video advertising at Google, announced the changes to Google’s retargeting system for 2016:</p>
<p><i>“We’re introducing cross-device remarketing for Google Display Network and DoubleClick Bid Manager to help you reach the same user across devices, apps and sites. You can now tell a single story to your audience and decide how frequently they see your ad across devices.”</i></p>
<p>The shift, which follows Facebook’s lead, means the advertiser can retarget users taking into account <b>access from different devices.</b> This will be limited to users signed into their account. This means being able to display ads for products on multiple devices, provided they are accessed from the same account.</p>
<p>Until now, all steps forward by Google in cross-device retargeting have focused on resolving the problem of conversion metrics where the user has browsed from multiple devices. According to a study conducted in the United States,<b> 60% of conversions start on one device and end on another</b>.<b> </b>If most online conversions involve multiple devices, it is no surprise that Google has begun to move in this direction.</p>
<p>But there’s more to it than conversion improvements. Until now, control over frequency capping was per device, but with cross-device retargeting merchants will be able to <b>think about marketing strategies attuned to the user</b>, rather than the device used.</p>
<p>All these changes have a direct consequence: <b>improved control of one’s advertising budget, visibility and ROI from retargeting</b>, with much cleaner and clearer segmentation. Why? Because these improvements not only report cookie-based search interests, but focus on targeting actual individuals. With these changes, a marketing strategy based on retargeting is much more effective, not only for conversion, but also in terms of investment.</p>
<h4 style="color: #5cc6ff">Why has Google made these changes to retargeting now?</h4>
<p>Google has always been fairly restrictive with advertisers regarding leveraging user data. It provided plenty of data, but leveraging it has always been somewhat rudimentary, particularly compared with other platforms, like <b>Facebook</b>. The social network <b>has been one of the companies leading the way in this area </b>(one of its great advantages when selling is retargeting between advertisers) and it seems that Google has decided to follow suit and offer its advertisers a much more practical way of leveraging user data.</p>
<p>With e-commerce and m-commerce on the rise, our potential customers are everywhere at once, and this must also be reflected in retargeting and other marketing strategies. Our customers start on their mobile, but complete their purchase three hours later on their tablet, or they discover our shop on their office computer and then buy on their mobile on their way home. With this change in how new technologies are used, it was clear that <b>the traditional approach of cookie-based retargeting had become obsolete.</b></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/cross-device-retargeting-reaching-customers-devices/">Cross-device retargeting: reaching customers on all their devices</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/cross-device-retargeting-reaching-customers-devices/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Succeed your marketing campaigns with Google Shopping</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/succeed-marketing-campaigns-google-shopping/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/succeed-marketing-campaigns-google-shopping/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 08:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22350</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Google Shopping helps businesses like you tap into the power of customer intent to reach the right people with relevant products ads, when it matters the most. With Google Shopping, put your product images, price, and business name right in front of people searching on Google, no matter what device they’re using. This module helps [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/succeed-marketing-campaigns-google-shopping/">Succeed your marketing campaigns with Google Shopping</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xIil1YlBMOw">Google Shopping</a> helps businesses like you tap into the power of customer intent to reach the right people with relevant products ads, when it matters the most. With Google Shopping, put your product images, price, and business name right in front of people searching on Google, no matter what device they’re using.<span id="more-22350"></span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/11/article_google_shoping.jpg"><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/11/article_google_shoping.jpg" alt="article_google_shoping" width="850" height="560" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22351" /></a><br />
<a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/23831-google-shopping.html">This module</a> helps you save time and extra work by using your existing PrestaShop account to automatically submit data to fuel your Google Shopping campaigns. With just a few clicks, your product data is populated in your feed to show on Google &#8212; helping you reach millions of new customers searching for what you sell.</p>
<p>Benefits:</p>
<ul>
<li>Minimize workload and go-to-market time: Use the product information you already have in PrestaShop without needing to create separate files to submit to Google</li>
<li>Data accuracy: Continuously import fresh data from your store on PrestaShop without any additional work</li>
</ul>
<p>To get started, click the button / link below to sign up. A new PrestaShop API account will be created and the credentials securely sent to Google Merchant Center. Google will use this information to retrieve store details and contact information to pre-fill the signup form. If you choose to not create a Google Merchant Center account, this information will be deleted after 60 days.</p>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/23831-google-shopping.html">Register</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/succeed-marketing-campaigns-google-shopping/">Succeed your marketing campaigns with Google Shopping</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/succeed-marketing-campaigns-google-shopping/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 keys to a successful marketplace strategy</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-keys-successful-marketplace-strategy/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-keys-successful-marketplace-strategy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 06:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22308</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Marketplaces can be a boon for small online companies just starting out, but they can also be overwhelming. It’s easy to feel invisible amidst the competition that thrives within the ecosystem of an industry giant like Amazon. Fear not. In today’s video, Nicolas Maufrais, PrestaShop Agencies Partnership Manager with Shopping Flux gives you a technical [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-keys-successful-marketplace-strategy/">5 keys to a successful marketplace strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Marketplaces can be a boon for small online companies just starting out, but they can also be overwhelming.<br />
It’s easy to feel invisible amidst the competition that thrives within the ecosystem of an industry giant like Amazon.<span id="more-22308"></span></p>
<p>Fear not. In today’s video, Nicolas Maufrais, PrestaShop Agencies Partnership Manager with Shopping Flux gives you a technical and marketing toolkit to get the most out of marketplaces, from first sale to international development.</p>
<div class="g-ytsubscribe col-centered text-center" data-channelid="UCqDSbqSbkboMBARlYrhNa7g" data-layout="full" data-count="default"></div>
<p><iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pDMsybvLtQk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div class="text-center"><a class="btn" style="background-color: #cd201f;border: 1px solid #b31217;border-bottom: 3px solid #b31217;margin: 20px 0 0;color: #fff" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/prestashop?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=article&amp;utm_campaign=youtube&amp;utm_content=shopping flux"> Watch more videos</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-keys-successful-marketplace-strategy/">5 keys to a successful marketplace strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-keys-successful-marketplace-strategy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
